schunk.com 2016-09-03

# Privacy Policy

SCHUNK GmbH & Co. KG, Bahnhofstr. 106 – 134, D-74348 Lauffen/Neckar, Germany (“Schunk”), collects and uses your personally identifiable information strictly in accordance with the provisions of the Data Privacy Act of the Federal Republic of Germany. Below we explain the methods, scope and purpose of collecting and using personally identifiable information.

Collection and saving of data for internal systems and statistical purposes 

Every time you access our website, your internet browser will automatically send the following information to our web server for technical purposes: 

This information is stored anonymously and is used for statistical purposes (such as determining how often each page on our site is visited) or for monitoring our networks and systems to detect server malfunctions (log files). 

Other information 

Other information is collected and processed only to justify, establish or modify a contractual relationship between you and SCHUNK. We will use the information collected for this purpose only as necessary to fulfill the terms the contract. 

If you send us a message using the contact form on our website, we will store and use the information provided on the form (name, postal or email address, phone number, etc.) to provide the services you requested and to further correspond with you. 

Please note that correspondence via email or the contact form is not a secure means of communication and that the content is not protected against unauthorized access by third parties. For confidential information, we recommended using regular mail. 

Consent 

If we wish to collect, process or transmit personally identifiable information for purposes other than those cited above, we will obtain your express and voluntary consent before doing so. Even if you do not grant consent, you will still be able to use our website to the extent that this is technically and legally possible. 

You may revoke your consent to the further use of your personally identifiable information at any time with future effect. To revoke your consent, please email us at [datenschutz@de.schunk.com](mailto:datenschutz@de.schunk.com). 

Transfer of personally identifiable information to third parties 

We will use your personally identifiable information for internal purposes as described above. Information is not provided to third parties. 

If we hire a third party to process business transaction information on our behalf, we must obligate said third party to comply with our information privacy standards and to give us the right to verify compliance with these standards as well as applicable laws. In this case, SCHUNK also remains legally responsible for complying with the provisions of the Data Privacy Act ("Contract Data Processing"). 

Security measures 

SCHUNK has taken specific organizational and technical security measures to protect your personal information. These security measures reflect the current state of technology and are constantly updated in accordance with new advances. All employees who come into contact with personally identifiable information are obligated to comply with the provisions of the Data Privacy Act and are trained on the legal requirements. 

If information is collected in order to establish or fulfill a contractual relationship, our communication with you will be encrypted using the latest technology to prevent abuse by third parties. 

Storage and deletion of personal data 

All the personally identifiable information about you that we collect—as soon as it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected—will be immediately and irrevocably deleted unless we are required to keep it for legal reasons. If we are required to keep it, the information will be deleted once the legally prescribed storage period expires. 

Cookies 

We sometimes use "cookies" on our website. Cookies are small text files that our web server deposits on your computer. These cookies are used to recognize your computer next time you visit our website and to let the server know when you last visited and what pages you visited on our site. Cookies do not contain personally identifiable information, nor are they linked to any other personally identifiable information that we store. Cookies can only identify the computer but not the person or user that visits the site. 

However, if you prefer not to accept cookies, you can learn how to disable cookies via the Help function in your browser. Doing so will not limit your ability to use our site. 

Google Analytics 

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies," text files that are stored on your computer, to analyze your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the site is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, if IP anonymization is activated on this website, Google will abbreviate your IP address inside member states of the European Union or the European Economic Area before transmission. Only in exceptional cases will your full IP address be sent to a Google server in the USA and abbreviated there. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to analyze your use of the site, create reports on website activity and provide additional services to the site operator related to website and internet use. The IP address obtained from your browser by Google Analytics will not be combined with other Google data. You can prevent cookies from being stored by adjusting your browser settings; please note, however, that doing so may prevent you from fully using all of the functions of this website. You may also prevent the information generated by the cookie regarding your use of the website (including your IP address) from being sent to or processed by Google by opting out. To do so, you must download and install the browser plugin available from the following link: Legal Notice). 

Updating of this data protection declaration 

Schunk reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy as needed to reflect advances in technology or new products and services. The latest version is available for viewing at all times on this website.
